Finding Aid for Frank R. Kennedy Papers
Bentley Historical Library
- Other Organizational Affiliations
  The ABA papers focus primarily on his work on the Ad Hoc Committee to Study the Federal Priority in Insolvency. Those papers are organized in reverse chronological order. For the most part they consist of correspondence with other members of the committee. The American College of Bankruptcy is an honorary professional and educational association of bankruptcy and insolvency professionals. The purpose of the organization is to set standards for achievement and professionalism. In 1996, Professor Kennedy was the first recipient of the College's Distinguished Service Award. The papers consist primarily of correspondence on bankruptcy issues. Professor Kennedy was a life member of the ALI, which is an educational association that promotes clarification and simplification of the law and encourages scholarly legal research. The papers consist primarily of newsletters, annual reports, and correspondence. The Rotary papers include chapter histories for the Ann Arbor, Michigan chapter and membership directories. There is also information regarding the establishment and operation of the chapter's endowment fund. There are also the personal Rotary papers of Professor Kennedy which include the certificate granted to him as a Paul Harris Fellow of Rotary International.
  - American Association of University Professors (Box 17)
  - ABA Ad Hoc Committee to Study the Federal Priority in Insolvency, 4 folders (Box 17)
  - ABA Business Law Section (Box 17)
  - American College of Bankruptcy
    - 1995-1997 (Box 17)
    - 1998 (Box 17)
    - Distinguished Service Award (Box 17)
  - American Law Institute (Box 17)
  - Association of American Law Schools (Box 17)
  - Order of the Coif (Box 17)
  - Rotary
    - Activities and Honors (Box 17)
    - Endowment Fund
      - Correspondence (Box 17)
      - History (Box 17)
      - Tax Exemption (Box 17)
    - Histories (Box 17)
    - Membership Directories (Box 17)
- Teaching
  The eighth series, Teaching, (.5 linear feet) contains papers relating to the courses and the seminars taught by Professor Kennedy while at the University of Michigan Law School. The four subjects covered in this set of papers are: financial reorganization, consumer credit transactions, debtor's and creditor's rights, and debtor's reorganization. In general the papers are annotated outlines, exams, assignments, and a casebook from the courses.
  - Courses
    - Financial Reorganization, 1959 (Box 17)
    - Consumer Credit Transactions, Annotated Coursepack, 1976 (Box 17)
  - Seminars
    - Debtor's and Creditor's Rights, 1977 (Box 17)
    - Debtor's Reorganization, 1974; 1983; 2 folders (Box 17)
- Uniform Fraudulent Transfer Act
  The ninth series, Uniform Fraudulent Transfer Act, (.5 linear feet) contains committee proceedings and correspondence of the original drafting meetings for the UFTA. Professor Kennedy was the reporter for the UFTA committee. The papers also contain research and analysis on the topic of UFTA performed by Professor Kennedy as a consultant for the states of Pennsylvania and West Virginia, which were addressing the issue of adopting a fraudulent transfer act for their respective states.
  - Committee Proceedings
    - Florida, 1983 (Box 18)
    - Colorado, 1984 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence
    - Committee Members, 1979-1997 (Box 18)
    - General, 1982-1995; 6 folders (Box 18)
  - Research, 1984-1988 (Box 18)
  - State Legislation
    - Pennsylvania, 1993-1994 (Box 18)
    - Virginia, 1987-1993 (Box 18)
- Writings and Research
  The tenth series, Writings and Research, (9.5 linear feet) contains sub-series of articles, collected research, speeches, workshops, and research for lectures. The articles, speeches and workshops are all works written by Professor Kennedy. The collected research topics include: "Fresh Start" provisions, international comparative law of bankruptcy, and municipal debt adjustment. Also within the collected research sub-series is research done by Antonio Bautista, Professor Kennedy's research assistant from the Philippines, on the topics of the Uniform Commercial Code and bankruptcy, as well as the Bankruptcy Laws. Also included in collected research are six volumes of a casebook on creditors' rights written by Edgar Durfee, Professor Kennedy's predecessor at the University of Michigan, and inherited by Professor Kennedy when he came to Michigan. The final sub-series is the research for lectures, this is a collection of seven linear feet of articles, citations, and notes collected by Professor Kennedy from the 1960s through the 1980s. The series covers a wide range of topics in business law, creditor law, and commercial law. The papers were used as the basis for lectures and topics for discussion, as well as for background research for his writing.
  - Articles
    - "Administration of Partnership and Partners Cases,", 1997 (Box 18)
    - "A Brief History of Bankruptcy", circa 1994 (Box 18)
    - "Claims: Definitions, Filing and Priority" (outline), 1996 (Box 18)
    - "Commencement of a Bankruptcy By or Against a Partnership or Partner,", Undated (Box 18)
    - "Commencement of Cases,", 1996 (Box 18)
    - "Discharge of Partnerships and Partners Under the Bankruptcy Code,", 1997 (Box 18)
    - "The Debtor's Fresh Start Under the Proposed New Bankruptcy Act", 2 folders (Box 18)
    - "Moore's Casebook on Debtor's and Creditor's Rights", circa 1965-1966; 3 folders (Box 19)
    - "Partnerships and Partners Under the Bankruptcy Code" (outline), 1997; 3 folders
      - Correspondence, 1997 (Box 19)
    - "Reorganization of the Partnership Debtor Under Ch. 11 or 12,", 1997 (Box 19)
    - "Sections 361 and 362: Automatic Stay and Adequate Protection" (outline), 1996 (Box 19)
    - "Section 364: Obtaining Postpetition Credit" (outline), 1996 (Box 19)
    - "Section 365: Executory Contracts and Leases" (outline), 1996 (Box 19)
    - "Use or Disposition of Property 11 U.S.C. Sec. 363" (outline), 1996 (Box 19)
    - Washington University Law Quarterly, 1937-1939 (Box 19)
  - Collected Research
    - Annotated Bankruptcy Articles (Box 19)
    - Annotated Publications (Box 19)
    - Antonio Bautista, 1963-1967 (Box 19)
    - Bankruptcy Treatise Fellowship Application (Box 19)
    - Durfee, Edgar "Cases on Creditors' Rights", 6 folders (Box 19)
    - "Fresh Start" Provisions, 1971-1974 (Box 20)
    - International Comparative Law of Bankruptcy, 1970-1996; 8 folders (Box 20)
    - Municipal Debt Adjustment, 1975-1976; 2 folders (Box 20)
  - Speeches
    - "Debtors and Creditors" World Bank, 1990 (Box 20)
    - "Due Process Limitations on Creditor's Remedies,", 1970 (Box 20)
    - "Equity" University of West Virginia (Box 20)
    - "Federal Tax Liens, Levies and Collections: Effect of Insolvency and Bankruptcy" (Box 20)
    - "New Bankruptcy Act,", 1980 (Box 20)
  - Workshops
    - "Basic Bankruptcy" ICLE, 1975 (Box 20)
    - "The New Bankruptcy Rules" ICLE, 1974 (Box 20)
    - New York University: Bankruptcy and Business Reorganization (Box 20)
  - Research for Lectures, circa 1960s-1980s
    - Attachment and Garnishment (Box 20)
    - Attorney's Fees (Box 20)
    - Bills and Notes (Box 20)
      (no. 1 of 3 folders)
    - Bills and Notes (Box 21)
      (nos. 2-3 of 3 folders)
    - Chattel Security Instrument (Box 21)
    - Class Actions, 4 folders (Box 21)
    - Commercial Speech (Box 21)
    - Consumer Credit, 6 folders (Box 21)
    - Consumer Protection, 6 folders (Box 21)
    - Credit Cards, 4 folders (Box 22)
    - Credit Reporting, 2 folders (Box 22)
    - Debit Cards (Box 22)
    - Debt Collection, 6 folders (Box 22)
    - Default and Acceleration (Box 22)
    - Defenses (Box 22)
    - Due On Sale, Land Contracts, Home Mortgages (Box 22)
    - Electronic Funds Transfer (Box 22)
      (no. 1-2 of 4 folders)
    - Electronic Funds Transfer (cont.) (Box 23)
      (nos. 3-4 of 4 folders)
    - Equal Credit Opportunity Act, 3 folders (Box 23)
    - Extra-Legal Protection of Consumers, 2 folders (Box 23)
    - Federal Department of Agriculture, 2 folders (Box 23)
    - Federal Trade Commission (Box 23)
      (nos. 1-6 of 15 folders)
    - Federal Trade Commission (Box 24)
      (nos. 7-15 of 15 folders)
    - Fraud (Box 24)
    - General, 4 folders (Box 24)
    - Government Protection (Box 24)
      (nos. 1-2 of 5 folders)
    - Government Protection (cont.) (Box 25)
      (nos. 3-5 of 5 folders)
    - Holder in Due Course, 2 folders (Box 25)
    - Judgment/Inconvenient Forum (Box 25)
    - Judicial Enforcement of Security Interests (Box 25)
    - Mechanic's Liens (Box 25)
    - Non-Judicial Foreclosure, 2 folders (Box 25)
    - Odometer Law (Box 25)
    - Pre-Code Security Interests in Shifting Collateral (Box 25)
    - Proceeds (Box 25)
    - Product Liability (Box 25)
      (nos. 1-6 of 8 folders)
    - Product Liability (cont.) (Box 26)
      (nos. 7-8 of 8 folders)
    - Punitive Damages (Box 26)
    - Reimbursement (Box 26)
    - Remedies, 7 folders (Box 26)
    - Sales Financing Devices (Box 26)
    - Security, 9 folders (Box 26)
    - Strict Liability (Box 27)
    - Subrogation (Box 27)
    - Surety's Rights in Liquidation (Box 27)
    - Suretyship, 3 folders (Box 27)
    - Unconscionability, 2 folders (Box 27)
    - Unfair and Deceptive Trade Practices (Box 27)
    - Wage Garnishment and Assignment, 2 folders (Box 27)
    - Warranties, 9 folders (Box 27)